CURRICULUM VITAE

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name: Nancy Njoki Mwangi

Address: P.O. BOX 635-10106, OTHAYA.

Tel No: +254723081591

Alternative No.: +254732380615

Email: <u>kinjonancym@gmail.com</u>

nancienjokim@gmail.com

Birth date: 1st July, 1993

Status: Single

Nationality: Kenyan

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am an energetic and enthusiastic person who enjoys and loves a challenge and achieving personal goals. I am matured and have qualities to bring to work place such as good team work, team leader, organizational skills, managerial skills, efficiency and I am very meticulous. I show pride in all the work I do and work well under pressure or no pressure. I possess excellent verbal and written communication skills and am able to relate to a wide range of people. All these skills have been enhanced during all the work experiences I have gained.

EDUCATION

SEPT. 2012-APRIL 2016: Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

(BSc. Industrial Biotechnology- 2nd Class Honors)

JAN-FEB 2012: SAMFRITECH Computer College

(8 COMPUTER PACKAGES)

- Microsoft Office Word
- Microsoft Office Excel
- Microsoft Publisher
- Microsoft PowerPoint
- Microsoft Access
- Adobe PageMaker
- Microsoft Office Outlook
- Programming

2008-2011: KAHUHIA GIRLS HIGH SCHOOL (B+)

1998-2007: ST. THOMAS CATHOLIC ACADEMY. (379 MKS)

WORK EXPERIENCE

JAN 2021 TO DATE: REVITAL HEALTHCARE (EPZ) LTD.

Quality Assurance Manager

DUTIES:

- Ensuring that all products (medical devices) meet legislative requirements.
- Studying scientific and legal documents and preparing documentation.
- Gathering, evaluating, organizing, managing and collating information in a variety of formats.
- Ensuring compliance with regulations set by regulatory authorities/bodies.
- Maintaining familiarity with company product ranges.
- Planning, undertaking and overseeing product trials and regulatory inspections.
- Keeping up to date with changes in regulatory legislation and guidelines.
- Analyzing complicated information, including trial data.
- Offering advice about company policies, practices and systems.
- Obtaining marketing permission.
- Outlining requirements for labelling, storage and packaging.
- Using a variety of specialist computer applications.
- Liaising and negotiating with regulatory authorities.
- Providing advice about regulations to manufacturers/scientists.
- Writing comprehensible, user-friendly, clear product information leaflets and labels.
- Ensuring that quality standards are met and submissions meet strict deadlines.

JAN 2020 TO DEC 2020: REVITAL HEALTHCARE (EPZ) LTD.

Assistant Quality Assurance Manager

DUTIES;

- Developing, training and monitoring the staff ability in handling Quality as a key aspect in a production facility
- Validate quality processes by establishing product specifications and quality attributes; documenting evidence; determining operational and updating quality assurance procedures/manual.
- Conduct regular internal audits of the production environment to ensure compliance to customer and internal standards and putting in place all corrective actions that arise from such audits within the stipulated time frame.
- Communication of responses to customer complaints and in-charge of all product mock recalls

- Communication of information relating to quality and technical matters within the company and flagging any non-conformance regarding to quality, safety or legality of the products.
- Overseeing the maintenance of the facility hygiene to the highest standards and ensuring adherence to the cleaning programs
- Heading Quality Team on site and overseeing the Hygiene surveillance, all site micro testing and follow up on all corrective actions.
- Ensure complete compliance to prescribed standards
- Co-ordination of all New Product Development on site, follow up of results and product launches.
- Reviewing the performance of quality team

JULY 2018 TO DEC 2019: REVITAL HEALTHCARE (EPZ) LTD.

Assistant Quality Control Manager & IPQC

DUTIES;

- Control and monitor quality of products at all stages as per the WHO, GMP and ISO standards.
- Creating and enforcing compliance to the company's Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs)
- In process quality control through written procedure.
- Control of non- conforming material and their disposition while taking corrective and preventive measures.
- Ensuring critical instruments are well calibrated, well maintained and safely stored.
- Maintaining inventory of laboratory reagents, chemicals, and Media preparation for microbiological tests.
- Recommend adjustments to assembly or production process.
- Monitor operations to ensure they meet production standards.
- Carrying out microbiological tests on finished products and compiling quality reports as per ISO standards.
- Preparation of certificates of analysis for reporting chemical and analytical results.
- Analyzing incoming raw material according to specifications.

SEPT 2017 TO JUNE 2018: KENYA AGRICULTURE AND LIVESTOCK RESEARCH ORGANIZATION-KARLO

Assistant Research and Lab Analyst

DUTIES:

- Collection of samples for analysis
- Carrying out analysis and giving reports of the results found

DEC 2016 TO MAY 2017: SANLAM KENYA.

Personal Financial Advisor

JULY TO SEPTEMBER 2016: EAST AFRICABREWERIES LIMITED.

Intern- Raw Materials and Analytical Sensory, Quality Department.

EXPERIENCES:

- Quality management Raw materials Laboratory
- Analytical techniques Analytical Laboratory
- Equipment verifications Analytical Laboratory
- Food safety and food maintenance
- Product marketing and promotion.
- Providing quality products and services to the competitive local and global marketplace.
- Standard operating procedures.
- Being in the world of work.
- Working outside ones comfort zone.

JUNE-SEPT. 2015: DIRECT SALES MAXIMUM MARKETING LIMITED (DSMAX. LTD.)

Sales Executive.

ROLES AND EXPERIENCES;

- Organizing sales visits.
- Demonstrating and presenting goods.
- Establishing new businesses.
- Selling the company's products and services.

AUGUST 2014: KENYA AGRICULTURE AND LIVESTOCK RESEARCH ORGANIZATION.

Attachee Horticulture Laboratory.

ROLES AND EXPERIENCES;

- Microbiological propagation of plantlets.
- Analysis of research samples such as soils, plants and water.
- Capacity building through mentorship sessions.

JUNE-JULY 2013: NAKUMATT HIGHRIDGE, WESTLANDS NAIROBI

Sales Marketer and Product Promoter

EXPERIENCES.

- Creating/having good rapport with customers.
- Convincing the customers that my product is the best and making them buy.

FEB-AUG. 2012: GICHAGI-INI SECONDARY SCHOOL

Peer teacher and Part time teacher, (Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Geography & Kiswahili)

TRAININGS

October 2019 - EN ISO TRAINING

- EN ISO 13485:2016, ISO 9001:2015, ISO 19011:2011 Awareness
- INTERNAL AUDITING of the QUALITY MANAGEMENT SYSTEM.

July 2019 - KENY TANZ TRADING

- Fire Equipment Training Programme

Aug 2019 – ST. JOHN AMBULANCE KENYA

- Emergency First Aid Course

VOLUNTARY WORK

I worked voluntarily with ROTARACT CLUB OF JKUAT in children homes, society clean-ups among others. Gained skills such as problem solving.

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

Sports: handball, hockey and athletics.

Hobbies: exploring new things and environments, travelling, reading novels, socializing, visiting the needy and old aged, computing.

REFERENCES

Mr. Ankur Vora

General Manager/Director Operations/MR – Revital Healthcare.

+254 711 443 366

Mrs. Lucycaster Muoti Regulatory Affairs Officer - Revital Healthcare +254 727 732 116

Dr. Henry Muriuki Kariithi Senior Biotechnologist – KALRO +17065 219 021- Atlanta, Georgia

Ms. Jane Waithera Line/Quality Manager, Quality Department Kenya Breweries Limited. +254 722 745 397